<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Computer History</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="ada">Born: December 10, 1815 in London, United Kingdom \n Died: November 27, 1852 in United Kingdom \n Nationality: British\n Occupation: Applied mathematician\n \n In her 1843 translation of an article on Charles Babbage\'s Analytical Engine, Ada Byron Lovelace (1815 &#8211; 1852) added notations three times the length of the original text. The \"Notes\" earned her a place in computer history when they were later recognized as the first detailed description of a computer, including what is now considered a software program. In recognition of her enlightened ideas that were over 100 years before their time, the United States Department of Defense named its Ada programming language after her in 1980. \n Though she was born the daughter of the notorious English Romantic poet, Lord Byron, Ada Byron Lovelace chose to pursue the more objective field of mathematics. She proved to be her father\'s daughter, though, for her sense of passion was arguably as strong as her father\'s, despite her mother\'s attempts to suppress any \"Byronic\" tendencies in her. She went against traditional Victorian society by studying mathematics, which was a discipline few women attempted. The height of her passion for mathematics can be seen in her \"Notes" on Charles Babbage's Analytical Engine, a calculating device that was never actually built. She wrote with tremendous insight and her ideas about the capabilities of an analytical engine became reality in twentieth-century computers and earned her a place in the history of mathematics and computer science.\n </string>
    <string name="ada_lovelace">Ada Lovelace</string>
	<string name="grace">Born: December 09, 1906 in New York, New York, United States\n Died: 1992 in Arlington, Virginia, United States\n Nationality: American\n Occupation: Computer scientist\n\n With the longest active military career, Rear Admiral Grace Hopper (1906&#8211;1992) was also known as Amazing Grace and the Grand Old Lady of Software. She played an instrumental role in the development of the COBOL computer programming language.\n\n Grace Hopper, who rose through navy ranks to become a rear admiral at age eighty-two, is best known for her contribution to the design and development of the COBOL programming language for business applications. Her professional life spanned the growth of modern computer science, from her work as a young navy lieutenant programming an early calculating machine to her creation of sophisticated software for microcomputers. She was an influential force and a legendary figure in the development of programming languages. In 1991, President George H. W. Bush presented her with the National Medal of Technology \"for her pioneering accomplishments\" in the field of data processing.\n</string>
    <string name="grace_Hopper">Grace Hopper</string>
</resources>
